CHRISTOPHER COPELAND

Maplewood, NJ 07040 | (862) 205-7872 | cjcopeland20@gmail.com

Website, Portfolio, Profiles

- https://chriscopeland.netlify.app/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-copeland-3aa599180/
- https://github.com/CJcrispy

Professional Summary

Tech-savvy Software Test Engineer with established test case creation and execution talents. Skilled at analyzing logs, generating thorough reports and identifying any failures. Comprehensive experience in both manual and automated testing with a great understanding of the software development process. Superb consultancy and communication skills.

Skills

- Python
- SQL
- AWS
- Selenium
- Linux
- Docker

- Jenkins
- Java
- Go
- MySQL
- Agile testing

Work History

Software Engineer in Test 2

12/2021 to Current

Eagleview Technologies – Rochester, NY

- Managed multiple tests projects of significant complexity
- Collaborated with other members of the Development Team to review the designs of systems, implement test plans, and test the quality of software product
- Created automated tests for web and API based applications
- Integrated automated test suites into deployment pipelines

Software Test Engineer

01/2021 to 11/2021

ASRC Federal - Moorestown, NJ

- Automated manual procedures using Python scripts
- Conducted manual tests based on specific requirements given

- Managed Jira stories according to scrum guidelines
- Enhanced test logging/documentation for easy readability and report generating
- Performed weekly regression tests

Software Developer 08/2020 to 03/2021

Accenture - West Chester, PA

- Migrated hosts for existing applications to east and west servers
- Refactored mobile app functionality for more ease of use
- Deployed new services via GoCD pipelines
- Created new Spring Boot services
- Assisted various teams to strengthen their core code

Software Developer 04/2019 to 07/2020

Revature – Tampa, Fl

- Utilized JavaScript to give functionality to web pages
- Employed the Angular framework to swap views in the application
- Implemented SHA-256 in Java as server-side security validation
- Crafted the application to follow REST standards
- Managed tables in database layer through PostgreSQL
- Configured JDBC and Hibernate to pass data to the database
- Worked in team environments while utilizing Agile practices
- Deployed projects on a CI pipeline using Git, Jenkins, and Amazon Web Services
- Managed Java project implementation through Maven.

Software Test Engineer

Comcast, Contracted, Revature – Englewood, CO

- Doubled production time by implementing test driven development
- Optimized test cases/documentation to improve clarity and onboarding
- Performed Regression, API, load testing on numerous applications using primarily automated testing methods
- Conducted weekly tests to go over the state of the apps
- Created UI test suites with Selenium and TestNG and REST API test collections in Postman
- Validated and verified new features and changes needed to be deployed
- Recognized for creating concourse pipelines and teaching fellow peers how to create pipelines
- Automated test suites to run in Concourse CI.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science

Kean University - NJ